okay so in total i have seven insurance
coverages
[Music]
hi everyone it's charm again from ready
to go philippines a channel about
personal finance entrepreneurship and
adulting health tools
in the last two videos we have covered
the basics of life insurance that's life
insurance 101
and also how to go about getting one
yourself
the thought process behind it and if you
haven't seen these two videos i will
link them up in the card so that you can
check them out after you watch this
video
for this week we will be capping off
this
supposedly one video idea that became
a three-part series about life insurance
with my insurance policies i will be
sharing my life insurances and my health
insurances as well
again as a disclaimer i am not a
financial advisor
i am not affiliated with any life
insurance
companies and this is not a sponsored
video
although insurance companies if you want
to reach out to me my email
is down below in the description so
yeah let's start the video
okay so i have seven insurances
or insurance coverages and i would be
listing them down in order of when i got
them
so the very first one is phic
that's my phil health insurance
corporation
and i have been paying for phil health
since i was
20 or 21 i can't exactly remember
but i think to average it because i
started out paying the minimum
i think i have been paying around four
to six thousand pesos a year now
and if you're not familiar with phil
health it's basically the government's
health insurance and as an
employee you are required to remit every
month
so that's what i've been doing so
basically what it covers
is based on case rates this is a similar
system that the hmo follows
the rates that they cover
will differ on case-to-case basis like
what
illnesses what check-ups what hospitals
are covered
and you can check them out and the link
that i will put
down below for the full list of benefits
as a full health contributor
so yeah i won't dive too deep into that
because i think majority of the people
has fill health and i can cover it
more in a separate video next i will be
talking about my life insurances and
actually made
a table in my bullet journal and the
table basically
shows me the insurance policy name
when i have to pay for it like what
months my annual premium
my life coverage my accident rider
coverage
my critical illness coverage and how
much the fund
value is when i plan to retire
which as you guys know my retirement
goal is 45
and it has here the fun value
for when i take a holiday or without
holiday
so meaning of the holiday is if you have
10 year to pay insurance policies
you can actually stop paying for it for
10 years
because presumably the fund value
can pay for the insurances for the rest
of your life
now if you choose to put more money into
your vul
then your investment will obviously grow
but as i
mentioned in my previous video i would
actually
prefer to invest directly to funds
now as compared to something that is
linked with an insurance
because i found that it can be a little
bit more expensive
okay so the first one that i got was my
axa
life basics and i got it when i was 23
years old back in 2016.
so the annual premium for this is 27 000
and it's a 15-year pay policy
so my life insurance coverage for this
or the death benefit
is 600 000 and this is covered until i
am
100 years old and this has a critical
illness rider of another 600 000 pesos
this covers me until 71 years old and
lastly
it has an accident rider that covers
1 million pesos until 70 years old
ok so this was invested in a fairly
moderate funds so with the premium
holiday that means i stopped paying
after 15 years i'm 38 years old by then
the fund value would be 450 000 pesos
and if i would continue paying seven
more years until i'm 45
by then the fund value would be 800 000
pesos
and again this is depending on how the
market performs
so this is just based on historical data
on how much their fund
grows so for this policy i pay it
quarterly that's 3 6 9 and 12.
so this was my very first vuls so as the
name suggests it's very
basic it's very broad so after two years
i got another
vul and that's the manual life affluence
builder
my annual premium for this is 51 050
pesos and
this is a 10-year pay insurance policy
and my life
coverage or death benefit is 250
000 pesos and i am covered until 74
years old
this doesn't have a critical illness
rider but my accident rider is another
000 pesos and i am covered for that
until i'm age 45.
so let's talk about this policy for a
bit i mentioned in my last video that i
made a mistake
of doing an aggressive vul
so basically as you can compare with my
axa
um the annual premium is almost double
the price
but the life insurance coverage
is less than half so that's because
majority of the money really goes to the
investment and not really the insurance
and later on i realized that i could
have just
easily opened a fund which i later on
did so i have a fund also with my new
life
i can talk about my investments in
another video
but basically i realized that it became
more expensive
because of that but because it's an
aggressive vul
at age 45 the estimated fund value
is at 1.3 million and
that's with holiday meaning i will only
be paying for 10 years
so it's definitely a higher fund value
because i'm also putting in more money
so i am paying this twice a year
but i have a promo with my credit card
that
the payment can be spread out to three
months
so instead of twice a year it's
two quarters a year so i'll be paying
january february march
and july august september okay
if that makes sense and that's because
of the city light
pay because i have the citibank credit
card
i will link down to good citibank credit
cards below if you guys
want to check that out it's definitely
lighter because again the i know premium
is quite big so at least i can divide it
into sex payments so the next policy i
got it a year
after that's 2019 it's the fwd
set for health so fwd is definitely
an up-and-coming life insurance company
but they've been hitting the top 15 top
10 in the philippines and they are very
millennial friendly
their app is very good their websites
very good
they're just very digital so i really
like that aspect
of fwd so the fwd set for health is a
whole life
insurance it doesn't have a fund value
or investment portfolio
so the annual premium is at 33 202
and that is a 10-year pay policy as well
and the life insurance coverage or death
benefit
covers 650 000 pesos up to age 75
and the critical illness can pay up to
three times
it has to be three different critical
illnesses they will
pay another 650 000 each time
so that's 650 000 times three possibly
and that's also until age 75 and this
doesn't have an accident rider
so the fun value for this when i hit 45
is around 200 000 pesos
so i pay for the fwd twice a year as
well
okay so if my axle was like a broad
basic life insurance
my manual life was geared towards the
investment
more and the fwd is geared towards the
health
more so the next one is also an
all-encompassing
broad life insurance and this is a whole
life insurance it also doesn't have a
fun
value or investment attachment to it
so this is the phil um aia all-in-one
insurance and i just got this this year
right before the lockdown actually
so the unknown premium for my filament
insurance is 54
589.77
pesos okay i think that already includes
my film vitality i will be talking about
that in a little bit
so this is a 20-year pay policy
the life coverage or death benefit of
this is at 2 million pesos and you are
covered up to 100 years old
the critical illness is also a 2 million
pesos but you are covered until 75
and the accident rider as well as 2
million pesos
until age 75. so the cash value for this
when i hit
45 is 774 000 pesos
so phil um also has this thing called
filam vitality
and what that basically is is that
it rewards you for being healthy
so for example you reach a certain
amount of steps a week or
a certain amount of workouts where they
can track your heart rate so you would
need a watch
that was though i'm not currently
wearing it but i usually wear
a fitness tracker and it basically
gives you around 200 pesos every week
and rewards you for hitting your goals
and the premise of that is because if
you are healthier it's less
likely for you to get sick which in
return would be
less likely for you to claim your
insurance benefits
so i think it's a really smart marketing
tool
and i really like that about um so i
always suggest it to people who always
work
out or who has an active lifestyle
okay so don't get me wrong i love all
my insurance companies and like i
mentioned
in my previous videos almost all the
insurance companies have the same
products it just really depends on how
they market
it and you know sell it to people so i
pay for this policy
quarterly so all my policies are
actually auto
credited to my credit cards so i don't
have
to remember and i won't forget to pay
any payments
so those are my four permanent life
insurances and the whole coverage
for it is 3.5 million pesos
for now i feel like it's sufficient but
i might increase it as i go maybe i will
get
a term life insurance next okay so i'm
just gonna include
here the sixth insurance is from my cimb
account so if you're not familiar if you
reach 100
000 pesos in cimb they will
automatically
give you a life insurance that's
equivalent to your adb
for up to 1 million pesos so you can get
a free life insurance from 100 000
to 1 million pesos and you just have
to renew it every month by maintaining
that
adb or average daily balance so
i also have a life insurance there so
since it depends on the adb
i would just say a minimum of at least
000 so it's like a free term life
insurance that you can get that renews
monthly alright so lastly
is my hmo that is covered by my company
which is also my employer and we have
maxi care so this renews by annually
meaning every six months
so since i'm part of the management or
the board of directors
so we pay 7867
every six months and that's for this hmo
or health maintenance organization so
the life insurance of this
is only 50 000 pesos but we really
mostly use it for the health care
services
and the maximum benefit limit for that
is 250
000 pesos a year and you can use this
based on case rates again similar to
phil health
so a lot of the health care services are
based on the
maximum benefit limit so for example if
you need
x-rays or ct scans or mris
and you have a prescription or it is
requested by your doctor
then those can be covered by the hmo so
they also have
case rates meaning some procedures
or some checkups or some tests
they will put a limit on it so for
example 10 000
pesos for one ice lasik
or something like that so they have a
whole
document or pdf that they're gonna give
you
that you can check for the coverage so
for my hmo as well i have
free animal checkups and dental checkups
and procedures as well
so definitely if you are employed then
make sure to ask your hr
what the benefits of your hmo are
so that you can also take advantage of
them so the reason
for my life insurance is because i'm a
breadwinner
and i wanted to serve as an income
replacement in case something happens to
me
so yeah you definitely have to assess
your own needs i've talked about that
in my previous video so you can check
that out as well
so yeah that's it for this week's video
i hope you enjoyed it
i've already talked about my personal
finance system
and now i shared you guys my insurances
so maybe next time i can also share to
you guys my investments my net worth
let me know if you guys are interested
in a little bit more
personal videos like that so yeah if you
like this video then please give it a
like and share it to your friends and
families
don't forget to subscribe to my channel
and ring the notification bell
so i know that adulting's already hard
but personal finance doesn't have to be
that's why i love making these videos
for you guys
and again this has been charm from
reddit adult philippines and i will see
you on my next video